Contact

Nebbegårdsbakken 52, 2400 København NV 40371757 (Mobile) grusinator@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/williamsandvej-hansen (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Panel

.NET

Databricks

Languages

Dansk (Native or Bilingual)

Tysk (Limited Working)

English (Professional Working)

William Sandvej Hansen

Data Engineer

Copenhagen, Capital Region of Denmark, Denmark

Summary

I have been working on various projects ranging from backend development to data engineering to data analysis. Mostly within engineering and energy sectors. I have a bit of GIS experience from various projects, well supported by my education in data processing within geospatial and remote sensing diciplines. Now adays its hard to not get a bit of cloud and devops under the skin as well. I am quite adaptive in terms of skills and competences, and not afraid to start out something that i might not know much about. In terms of personality, according to the "Insights" profile test, i am the "Helping Inspirer". creative, energetic and currious type. Sometimes a bit too quick and intuitive. But it has its qualities too.

Experience

Energinet

Data Engineer

December 2022 - October 2023 (11 months)

As a data engineer at Energinet, i was responsible for developing a data project collecting massive amounts of data from the energy island in denmark, from various providers. The main goal was to recieve, perform quality control, and deliver data to the developers wanting to bid on the project. In order to quality control and unpack these wide range of binary offshore sensor data files, we relied on spark and databricks to be able to scale, while at the same time allow for the flexibility of the various data formats. Just to name a few, GDB, DFSU, segy, xtf etc. Some of these datasets had to be unpacked for QC, analytics and visualization purposes, so in order to support geospatial data in spark i used sedona (geospark) to be able to store data in delta parquet format and to perform spatial partitioning on the dataset using geohashing, in order to improve read performance.

Ørsted
Data Engineer
March 2020 - November 2022 (2 years 9 months)
Copenhagen Area, Capital Region, Denmark

As a data engineer I have been developing a data validation component as a part of our data pipelines, with configurable inputs for what to validate, developed in python, relying on pandas as data abstraction, integrated using Azure Service Bus.

I have also been involved with the data modelling in order to provide easy to understand and consume data for various analytics tools. MS Sql Server, Rest api.

In order to do iterate faster when implementing the right data model, we used python, sqlalchemy and Sqlite, to implement a mock db, mimicking the production environment, and to test the changes before implementing it, avoiding changes in api and data pipeline.

I have also developed different data analytics and visualization tools in python using streamlit, Panel, Dash and bokeh, that helps engineers to make interpretations based on the data.

At Ørsted i have been using the SAFE framework for project management, Devops has been relying on Azure devops, Docker and K8S.

Netcompany

IT Consultant

November 2018 - November 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Københavnsområdet. Danmark

At Netcompany i have been working at big projects building custom IT solutions with multiple integrations. The primary tools that i have been using as a backend developer was Oracle, Groovy, REST and a bit of Javascript. For project management and version control Jira and Git with SCRUM.

NIRAS

Softwareudvikler

September 2016 - March 2018 (1 year 7 months)

Allerød, Capital Region, Denmark

parallel processing capabilities.

At Niras i have been developing geodata algorithms for data transformation, including processing of lidar data, and images. I have among other developed an image classifier that can identify buildings in spectral orthophotos.

I have also developed a model that can based on lidar and gis road data, identify the height profile of the roadsides, and identify the need and cost for cleaning the roadside. This was developed in C# using Postgres, postgis, with

At Niras i have also been developing various plugins for QGIS, using Qt and Python.

KK Wind Solutions
Engineer
March 2014 - August 2014 (6 months)
Ikast

At KK wind solutions I was hired for a project of a half year where I was investigating the effort of switching out a communication chip for the IO boards in the wind turbine control system. This was due to inducing flexibility in the product configuration. This project involved programming the chip in C, investigating communication protocols as Ethercat profinet etc.

Det Tekniske Fakultet, Syddansk Universitet Instructor September 2013 - January 2014 (5 months) Odense Area, Denmark

instructor in Electronics courses teaching basic analog circuit design.

VELUX

Internship Electronics February 2013 - June 2013 (5 months) Skjern - Denmark

During my time at Velux I developed a PCB for loading a solar panels. This PCB was meant for testing the durability of solar panels for the automated Velux windows.

Education

Danmarks Tekniske Universitet

Master of Engineering - MEng, Earth and Space Physics and

Engineering · (2014 - 2016)

Syddansk Universitet
Bachelor of Engineering (BEng), Electrical and Electronics
Engineering · (2010 - 2014)

Vejle Tekniske Gymnasium HTX, Science - Mathematics and Physics · (2007 - 2010)